#### WILLIAM MICHAEL RANKIN

william.rankin01@gmail.com

## ABOUT ME:

I am a full-stack web developer and software engineer and recently completed the University of Utah Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp. I have twelve years of experience as a laboratory chemist, and I am looking to change direction in my career. My experience in chemistry and in pharmaceutical R&D and manufacturing has given me practical skills that will transition to my new career in web and software development.

## These skills include:

- Detail-oriented problem solving, troubleshooting.
- Processing large data sets and reviewing others work on large data sets.
- Working and communicating with a team to complete large projects on a tight timeline.
- Working independently to complete small portions of a large collaborative project.

## SKILLS:

•	ΗΊ	$\Gamma N$	Ħ
•	111	L IV.	ட

- CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery

# • Express.js

- React.js
- Node.js
- MongoDB

## MySQL

- Git
- APIs
- GraphQL

## **EDUCATION:**

University of Utah Coding Bootcamp

April 2024

- Gained skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, jQuery, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, and Git.
- Worked together in teams to complete class projects.

Bachelor of Science, Chemistry

August 2014

Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah

- Completed courses in general, organic, physical, analytical, inorganic, and biochemistry.
- Completed lab courses in general, organic, physical, inorganic, and analytical chemistry.

#### EXPERIENCE:

Product Development Scientist

09/2019-Present

Teva Pharmaceuticals, Salt Lake City, Utah

- Operated instruments and analyzed large data sets to detect low level compounds in pharmaceutical products.
- Authored methods and protocols for analytical testing.
- Worked independently and with a team to accomplish goals within deadlines.

• Authored and review reports that are submitted to the FDA for pharmaceutical filing.

New Product Development Analyst

12/2017-09/2019

Reckitt Benckiser, Salt Lake City, Utah

- Coordinated with quality control, engineering, production, R&D, and planning teams to develop and produce new products in the factory.
- Authored and revised protocols and SOPs for laboratory procedures using Change Control
- Lead and authored OOS investigations.
- Worked with outsource laboratories to complete testing.
- Trained analysts on new methods

# On-going Stability Analyst

09/2016-

12/2017

Reckitt Benckiser, Salt Lake City, Utah

- Performed stability and commercial testing for VMS and OTC products in a GMP/GLP environment.
- Built and maintained instrument methods in instrument analysis software.
- Maintained instruments and associated software, including repairs, qualification, validation, and general troubleshooting for the laboratory.

Research Assistant University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah 08/2014-06/2016

Research Assistant

04/2011-08/2014

Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah

- Developed and documented new synthetic methods for nanoparticles.
- Eight-time recipient of Undergraduate Research Awards
- Presented research in ACS meetings and local conferences.
- Published research J. Nanosci. Nanotech. 2015, 15, 3809-3815.